<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>R on Stencilled</title><link>http://www.stencilled.me/tags/r/</link><description>Recent content in R on Stencilled</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>senthil.thyagarajan@gmail.com (Senthil Thyagarajan)</managingEditor><webMaster>senthil.thyagarajan@gmail.com (Senthil Thyagarajan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.stencilled.me/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get over that data fatigue</title><link>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2020-08-15-datafatigue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>senthil.thyagarajan@gmail.com (Senthil Thyagarajan)</author><guid>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2020-08-15-datafatigue/</guid><description>So you are looking at numbers everyday. These can be in excel sheets / google sheets while cleaning data or trying to get some insights out of the tables in various dashboards you see daily. These numbers might be currency , rates or just volume of any metrics you want to track.
So how would you find the outliers across these tables, the best peforming KPI&amp;rsquo;s , correlations between various metrics.</description></item><item><title>Whats Cooking ??</title><link>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2020-03-29-whatscooking/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>senthil.thyagarajan@gmail.com (Senthil Thyagarajan)</author><guid>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2020-03-29-whatscooking/</guid><description>This R shiny app is for all the home chefs out there looking to try different recipes, especially now that we are all social distancing and looking at ways to keep us sane! (Yes, cooking is a form of meditation wherein the end, you have something to eat :D). From a database of 28000 + recipes, just enter the ingredients you wish to filter on and the type of cuisine and you will see all the recipes with your specified ingredients from your favorite cuisine!</description></item><item><title>Styling DataTables</title><link>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2019-04-20-stylingdt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>senthil.thyagarajan@gmail.com (Senthil Thyagarajan)</author><guid>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2019-04-20-stylingdt/</guid><description>Most of the shiny apps have tables as the primary component. Now lets say you want to prettify your app and style the tables. All you need understand how tables are built using HTML. This is how the default datatable looks like in the app.
In order to build the html table I have used a function table_frame which can be used as a container in DT::renderdatatable. This function basically uses htmltools.</description></item><item><title>Edit datatables in R shiny app</title><link>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2019-04-18-editable/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>senthil.thyagarajan@gmail.com (Senthil Thyagarajan)</author><guid>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2019-04-18-editable/</guid><description>Tables are very much the standard way of representing data in dashboard along with visualizations. Wouldnt it be more useful if you could edit the values in the tables to trigger some calculations and update the values on the fly . These can be used for adjusting allocations or budgets in a project.
Libraries The libraries which we will be using are shiny for the app itself, dplyr and DT for displaying and editing the tables.</description></item><item><title>Download and Email reports in R Shiny app</title><link>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2019-04-14-downloadshiny/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>senthil.thyagarajan@gmail.com (Senthil Thyagarajan)</author><guid>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2019-04-14-downloadshiny/</guid><description>Most of the dashboards / R shiny app are viewed by the people who want to view the underyling data without doing much analysis. While they view the KPI&amp;rsquo;s , the charts and the tables it would be also an important for them to take the results out of the app for meetings and presenations. One of way doing it is the traditionally downloading the reports. But to make it one step easier they could also be given an option to email these reports.</description></item><item><title>Visualizing Airbnb listings.</title><link>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2017-10-25-airbnb-listing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>senthil.thyagarajan@gmail.com (Senthil Thyagarajan)</author><guid>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2017-10-25-airbnb-listing/</guid><description>In this day and age of so many sharing services like Uber and Lyft , pricey hotels are being replaced by Airbnb. Students, working people and travelers wouldn&amp;rsquo;t always want to pay a high price for staying a couple of nights at the Marriott and would rather stay at a place where that has the basic amenities needed for them at a reasonable price. In this project I am trying to understand the listings put on Airbnb on how the price varies by neighborhood ,house type and various other factors.</description></item><item><title>Taps near you</title><link>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2017-09-18-taps-near-you/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>senthil.thyagarajan@gmail.com (Senthil Thyagarajan)</author><guid>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2017-09-18-taps-near-you/</guid><description>While working on a couple of projects involving beer data I did land up at breweries association. They have a data set on all the breweries across the US. This raw html table was scrapped ,cleaned and geocoded using R. You can find the R Scripts which I used for this project here. Once the data was ready this was put to use by being displayed on a web mapping application built on js and bootstrap.</description></item><item><title>Maps and gifs</title><link>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2017-03-20-map-gif-r/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>senthil.thyagarajan@gmail.com (Senthil Thyagarajan)</author><guid>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2017-03-20-map-gif-r/</guid><description>As I have been using R for a while, one of the things I wanted to do was a time series map. Most of the time series maps I see have sliders to change the years. While looking at how to make time series maps I happened to lear how to make a GIF with a set of images.
So I thought, how about making an election based map over the past elections.</description></item><item><title>Top Beers in 2016.</title><link>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2017-02-22-topbeers2016/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>senthil.thyagarajan@gmail.com (Senthil Thyagarajan)</author><guid>http://www.stencilled.me/post/2017-02-22-topbeers2016/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>After completing my previous post on food I wanted to work on something which I have started to explore recently,craft beer.
A friend of mine introduced me to a beer club membership prior to which I never knew anything beyond the Corona&amp;rsquo;s .
Then began the collection and here it is, what have so far.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>